Reality is only the beginning.
Virtuality is a science fiction, tv movie, drama film directed by Peter Berg.
Twelve extremely talented men and women have been chosen to be part of the
Phaeton mission, a 10-year trek to explore a distant planetary system.
In order to endure the stress of being confined to their high-tech vessel, the crew passes the time
using advanced virtual reality modules that allow them to take on various identities.
But as the ship approaches a critical phase of their journey, a deadly flaw is discovered in the
virtual system, forcing them to question if someone onboard might be a killer.
Commander Frank Pike, played by Nikolaj Coster-Waldau.
Billie Kashmiri, played by Kerry Bishé.
Alice Thibadeau, played by Joy Bryant.
Manny Rodriguez, played by Jose Pablo Cantillo.
Dr. Jimmy Johnson, played by Ritchie Coster.
Dr. Roger Fallon, played by James D'Arcy.
Virtuality is a 2009 American science fiction drama television film directed
by Peter Berg and written by Michael Taylor and Ronald D.
Originally filmed for the Fox network as a television pilot for a series that was not
commissioned, it aired on the network as a standalone film on June 26, 2009.
It features the crew of Phaeton, a spaceship designed to search for a hospitable planet in
a nearby star system after an ecological catastrophe in near-future Earth.
While approaching the point of no return, the crew experiences problems with their virtual
reality entertainment system, which quickly escalate and threaten their mission.
The film explores themes of virtual reality, romance, space.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.